And here we are once again with a
new term that is going super
viral called loop Engineering.
Everyone is really talking about it.
We went from prompt Engineering to
Context Engineering to Arnest
Engineering which lasted very little
and now we have already entered this
new era of Open Engineering.  What
is it?  Is it all hype?  Is it marketing?
we'll find out in this video.
This new, let's say, paradigm was
launched by these two characters here
in the Tech world and I who are super
famous.  Let's talk about Boris Cerni, the
creator of Cloud Code, who in a
recent interview said these words
where he says that he no longer writes the
prompts on Cloud, but it is Cloud that
writes the prompts
itself through the loops it
creates.  His job now is to create
loops.  Peter Steinberger thinks
the same way.  He is the creator of
Open Clow, the most famous generalist people
in the world.  And with this post of his
ex he says "I remind you that you
should no longer do prompting agents, no
more, you must not do it anymore. You
should design the loops that
automatically prompt your agent.
Let's start now with the prompt engineering and
go through all the steps that led us
to loop engineering,
also explaining why we need this new way
of using AI agents. So let's start
with the prompt engineering which consisted
of writing
the system prompt, so you
wrote a prompt here in the model, okay? In order to
give it the
instructions. What do you write in this
prompt? You write you're a lawyer,
you're a front-end developer, you're a
personal assistant for customer
care. Once set up,
okay, which can be a prompt where you
give it the instructions, for each question,
for each question,
the model responds
and gives you the answer based on this
prompt that you set. And so there was this
whole prompt engineering
of how to write the prompt in the
best way so that the answer reflects
the instructions you gave it and we
spent a lot of time on this setup here
Prompt engineering is still being
done today. For example, this is
promptable
5, which was obtained through prompt
leaking, and we see a gigantic system prompt
that already takes up,
I think, 25,000 tokens. There are
instructions on what it should and shouldn't
do, examples of correct and
incorrect answers, a
lot of things are described, limitations, what it should
n't do, code snippets. Well,
to create
such a large prompt, they did prompt
engineering, and not only that, because they
themselves also declare in the
cookbooks the best way to
structure the prompt for certain
models. For example, this is the anatomy
of Clode prompt, so the task, context
files, references, success brief, roots,
conversation plan, and alignment. And so far,
so good. Now let's get into
Context Engineering. This is where we
worked the longest, because this is where
the context window comes into play. So,
each model has a window, the
Context Window, which is nothing more than the
memory that can manage the model,
meaning how many input tokens.  can
read. The system prompt, this one
we're going to define,
actually occupies a portion of
this context window. Okay? Everything
else is context and
information we can still
use. Typically, today's
frontier models can handle a
maximum of 1 million input tokens,
so we have a lot of room to
work with, but we'll always run into
the problem of filling
this context window. However,
with context Engineering, in addition to the
prompt, the
game is that the large language
model, the model that's here, becomes
an agent, so what can it do? It can
access folders,
so we have files,
we have the internet, the web, I write, and we have
apps.
And so now the agent, that is, the Large
Language Model, can autonomously
read and write and call
functions that allow it to
interact with the web, with files, and with
apps with the MCP protocol,
for example.
All these calls that are made
like "I want to see
what files are in this folder" and get the
response fill what is
actually the context of the model. So
people start to satisfy the  Its
requests to concatenate
all these tools that gradually
fill the context. So go to the
web, do the search and it fills the
context for you. Write me the report on the
local file and it fills the context for you. Go to
my CRM, then use the MCP, connect
to the app and this window here gradually
fills up. What's the problem? The
problem is that one
window has some
performance issues. This one here calls context
rot
and says that as the number
of input tokens increases,
performance degrades,
especially above 200,000 tokens,
like here at 200,000 tokens, performance
starts to degrade drastically
because there's so much text, so
many tokens in the
Context Windows that it starts to get confused
and so the context engineering
works and tries to
keep this context here as
compact as possible, that is, it tries to
shorten it or when
these tools are called it tries to get
shorter responses. Context
engineering works on this entire layer
here, that is, adding context from the
web app files with tools that can
call Large Language Model, but then it
works a lot.  On cleanliness, and
above all, there's a problem when we
do work that requires many
tools, so work that requires, eh,
a long time horizon. It's
inevitable that the context
fills up. Maybe we need more
context to work with, and so
what does context engineering do? It tries to
summarize
by doing the so-called
compaction. It tries to summarize the
context to try to free up space.
So now we've recovered this space
so we can continue
working, and then what does it do? It does
another compaction and recompacts again.
This whole approach is then
managed autonomously by the new
approach that was born, called
Harness Engineering.
Instead of doing the summary and then the
summary and then the summary, which still
loses a lot of performance
through the compaction described
here in the official
Cloud documentation,
Harness Engineering says, "Wait a
minute, why don't we create a whole
external structure to manage
the context effectively and efficiently.
So hardware engineering is really about
creating a framework
here on the outside,
so this becomes a
single component.  Then we create a framework here
externally
where, given the task,
a series of steps and files are structured
which each time practically
reinitialise our agent and make it
start from the point where it left off.
So step 2 continues, then
step 3, then step 4. And typically
this approach here from Arnness
Engineering is based on files that
are created by our agent
locally on our IPC, typical
MD files, so markdown files, so the
typical cloudmd
or the typical agents.md, MD, the fact of I do
n't know, the history, so the memory
punmd and all the folders.  Why not do this
without having to condense the context every
time, okay?  So when we go to
saturate it without having to compact it,
what people do is they write to
files themselves, they write to files what they have
done, they
empty all the memory
and they go and read the file every time
the session restarts so that it
has persistent memory on the files.
And that's where all this
Markdown file management came from.  For
example, going to see OpenClow, which
people are the most famous in the world, if you go and
look for documentation on how
OpenClow's memory works, you'll see that it has a
file called memory markdown, which
is the longterm memory, durable faxes,
preferences, decisions, then there's a
folder called memory where it
creates markdown files with the year, month and
day which are nothing more than all the
chats, everything you do is
written right into the file, so
the context isn't filled because it's
flashed streamed.  there then you have the file
called Dreams.md which is optional
which is the Dream Diary.  Then you can
set a lot of other memories on it, but
they're all files.  The file system is used
as an extension of the Windows context
of the model and then the model is given
tools such as memory search,
memory get to be able to search in
those files and dynamically read
what it needs.  Well, the memory
search is done both, um,
semantically, you know, using semantic search,
but also by having it [clear throat]
directly read the file that was
written to the file system.
So Harness Engineering is all
this scaffolding that is added
that structures the task into subtasks and for
each subtask we have the entire
model context window which is then
filled, then it ends here, then
we move on to step 2, this is all
emptied and we move on to work on step 2
and obviously so on until the
final goal is reached.
Let's do some tests so you can better understand
what color Ferrari is made of.
This request here only expects
a response via prompt engineering,
so we'll use knowledge of the
model to get the response.  They are
famous for their red, specifically their
racing red.  And he explains it to us.  So in
this first prompt we
just did prompt engineering
by just calling the model and we
got the answer.  We didn't use
any tools.  Whereas now if I
ask him what the name of the latest model
launched by Ferrari is,
by asking him this question now he
will use tools, so
let him check the latest news
.  This is already context
engineering, it's calling tools to
get context information.  So
in this case now this is step
one, step 2
we are also using all
the tools,
so we see that now here is the
electric Ferrari also called light,
much discussed and here we have the
quotes.  While for Arnest Engineering I
should tell them to clone the Ferrari website for me
as it is.
With this request now, given that the
Ferrari site is very complex,
it's not a simple site,
we need all that component
to manage the development and
all the components it has to do, it has to
copy from the site.  So now
Arnest Engineering comes into play, so step
3 which structures the task into subtasks.
Obviously this request is
so large that it wouldn't fit
into a million
contexts, so it needs to be structured into
subtasks and everything needs to be managed via
Arnest Engineering.  Well, then here
starts Nav Baro, range of models, part
of structuring the whole site.  And now I
introduce you to loop engineering, which has been much
talked about and discussed in recent
times.  Let's start from the fact that basically
when the large language model calls
its tools and receives responses,
this is already a loop, okay?  Because it can
cycle through its tools.  This is a loop.
Not only that, but when we then use Arnest
Engineering, this other piece, this one
here is another loop because because
we loop until all the tasks have
been eh solved.  Okay, so this is a
loop, this is a loop, and now
what do we do with loop engineering?  We take
all of this and put it into
another loop,
a loop on top of a loop on top of a loop.  This is
loop engineering and you might be
thinking it's exaggerated, three loops one on top of
the other, but do we really need
all these loops?  And actually,
loop engineering makes sense and is an
extremely interesting approach
because making loops up here avoids you
having to make all these
requests and get the answers every time because it
's the agent itself that asks the questions and
answers.  That is, you start with the
first request, set up the loop, and from there on
the model cycles and basically
all the artifact fits into a loop.   Let's
immediately give some practical examples,
so that the concept remains fixed in your mind.
So, for example, create a web page
like a World Cup portal with all the
matches and let's keep a theme in mind
that there is the World Cup, part of your
Gente, Codex, Cloud Code, Antigravity and
through Ernest Engineering with the
whole eSapp,
okay?  and it creates the application for you, which is this one
here.  Now, for example, we can
make a loop, so we can put
the application in a loop
where for every news item, for every new thing that
people have and fish for, it goes and rewrites all the
code of the app, fixes it,
improves it, updates the link and does everything.
So by deploying the app, we're putting
all of Arnest Engineering in a loop and,
for example, keeping
the application always up to date, without
us having to do this work.
Let's take another example.  Create me an app
where there is an assistant for meetings
and local meetings, then
harness engineering starts and creates my
application.
Let's say I made the application
open source, it's all on Gitab, it's
all beautiful, it's all open.  Now, for
example, I could put
the application through an Engineering loop,
where any issue opened on GitHub,
that is, any problem encountered
in the application,
this loop starts where it checks for
the error and writes the code again,
uses the tools and
the engineering loop starts again which works on
this application to improve it.
without me having to write the
prompt solve
this problem, it is directly
active, checks when it receives this
trigger like there is this error,
starts and eh fixes the application.
This approach of putting everything
inside loops can be used for
many use cases, not just
on applications.  For example, Andrew
Garpati was the first to create
such a structure for research,
so he called this project Auto
Research and in the end it is a loop
engineering, that is, he took and created an
entire ARNES, he put it inside a
cycle, inside a loop and where he
basically does a series of
experiments on the code until
a condition is reached, until
a goal is achieved.
So the loop is set up like this
.  He made a script where
the dataset is located, that is, the data is prepared
, a script where
the training loop is actually done, so
the model is trained,
the results are written into a
markdown file and the loop continues
until a final condition is reached,
such as I want
the model to train me and have a recall
higher than 90%.  or it ends with
a maximum limit of iterations or
hours that have passed.  This, for
example, is loop engineering and the
cool thing is that it's doing a loop over a
harness that carries with it all the
MCP servers, all the skills, all
that context and tools that it can
continue to use in the
next loop.  So loop engineering
ultimately relies on these steps.
We need to have a trigger, so
something that makes us start the loop.
So in the case of this application
it could be the issues on GitHub.
In the case of this other application,
it could be news that
comes to us via email, news that comes to us
via IP calls, news in any
way.   Once
the loop is triggered, the execution starts,
so here the arrest starts
to verify that the issue has been
resolved or that those news have been
implemented, there is a verification part
and then what has been done is written to a file
, such as memory, and we prepare
for the next loop.  next loop
that starts when there is a new trigger.
Trigger that can be set
manually like "Every day at
this time starts" or event-based, that is,
when a certain event occurs.
Loop engineering on the Cloud is really
simple to set up, there are two ways and
I have prepared a whole lesson inside
my academy where I show in detail
real use cases of loop engineering and
above all when it is useful and
when not to use it.  Anyway, the commands are sloop
space, in fact you put the interval and
the prompt, so interval, for
example, every morning at 9:00 take
the information from that part and
update the code, start tests bla bla bla
, or loop every week
or every and you put the time.  While
the other way is slg.  And here we can
put, for example, optimize all
the code of my web page so
that it can open in less than 100
misses
and then put the straight bar on it.  After
the straight bar condition, do a
maximum of 100 attempts
or do a maximum of 8
total attempts.  Why is this other
condition added?  Because let's say we
asked for something
impossible, maybe we'll never be able
to optimize the web page under 100
msec.  What happens is that it
enters an infinite loop and makes us
consume many many tokens, so we
always put another
termination condition on it.
The goal has to be something that
can be measured, okay?  For example, I said
to make the web page load under
100 msec.  It's something
testable, that is, you have to start it,
modify the code, then
actually test if it stays under 100
msec, if it's not then start with
the other loop.  Or I could tell him to
migrate
this service to that other part,
so it's verifiable because once he
's done the whole migration of the
whole package, then he knows whether he's
finished or not.  Or I could tell him,
"Score me
goals, train me on this Large
Language Model so that in the
validation set it achieves so many percent
accuracy."  Okay?  Then we
always put the other condition on it, at most
you make 1000 attempts, but these are
verifiable conditions and we
have to pay a lot of attention to the conditions.  And these
are the five levels of verification
specific to this part here.  We have
deterministic verification of the type
make me this application and it has to
compile without errors, okay?  It must not
give me errors.  This is a deterministic Bulean thing
, true false.  Then we have
the second step, rules and constraints such as
I want it to take under 100 milliseconds
or that the cure is above 90%
accuracy or that this program uses up so much RAM
or that the text is a
maximum of 100 characters long.  So
they are numerical rules and constraints, not
Bulean ones.  Then we have the delayed earthly truth
.  This is very interesting
because these are things that can be verified but that
Leai cannot verify right now.
For example, create me, I tell him slgol,
create me eh a post eh taking the latest
news to publish on LinkedIn and that it goes
viral, that it goes viral is a
vague condition, it's not something
deterministic, it's not something that has
rules.  So maybe I should
change it and tell him make me a post that
gets 300
reactions on LinkedIn, okay?
Oh, and keep improving so that I can reach
this goal again.
What people do is create the post,
upload it, but they have no way of
directly verifying that it has reached these 300
reactions, because the reactions perhaps
mature in 23 days and so in this
case the sloop is perfect
where you explain to them the objective of
each day then check my
latest posts made on LinkedIn and improve
your way of creating carousels in such a way
as to reach 300 eh reactions to
each post.
And so this is a perfect
delayed loop because because the result of the
post that you do now will see it when you
start maybe the next loop
or two subsequent loops will start.  And that's great
because the real world very often has
delayed results.  for example, that
the deployment doesn't have many problems,
that the customers are satisfied or that
the engagement is certain or "Optimize
this advertising campaign for me", that is,
how Gol tells him to optimize the
advertising campaign, but
we'll see the result in a few days.  So
real world answers.  Point four is very interesting
, that is, using the Large
Language Model as a judge.  For example, I
tell him, let me refactor the code
until you're satisfied.  So the
fact of being satisfied means that
in the goal phase, she
herself verifies that she assigns a value between 1, between
1 and 20, between 1 and 100, she decides, assigns
a value and decides herself whether she has
reached the conclusion or not.
An interesting use case of LLM as a
judge is when we want to clone, for
example, web pages, apps,
so we take a screenshot
of the real web page, then we give it the
web prompt, as previously said "Clone my
Ferrari and it will make you an app, ok? That's
close".  But very often when you
tell him to create the
Ferrari website for me, he doesn't exactly do it the
same way.  And so here we put it now
inside the loop
where the LM acts as a judge and I tell it
"You are inside the codebase of this
application here
slg
improves the application from the point of
view of the UI UX
so that it is exactly the same
as this image that I attach and you
attach this image here
eh
try up to eh 80 changes and for each
change show me the rendering of the
web page that you have that you have modified. And
then what does it do? It enters this loop
where it modifies the page,
then it reads the image again and makes a
comparison and it judges itself, says
"Ok, the real image with the
rendered image of the web page how
close are they?"
it says, "Eh, they are 0.30 apart". Ok,
then I make other changes and it makes other
changes, other changes and it makes other
changes. Maybe it gets to a point where
it judges itself that it is at 0.90 because
it sees that it has basically fixed everything
leaders and buttons, has put the same
effects, same font, put exactly
the same things. It says on purpose I have
arrived and I have finished. The  Loop
engineering basically eliminates the need for you to
intervene every time you write
prompts, "Improve this." No, do
that. No, improve this. No,
do that. You tell them
the goal directly.
It's obviously better if we go back to
this case, which is verifiable, it's
autonomous. This one is also more or less
fine because it's verifiable with a delay.
While in case four, you have it evaluated, you
have them, and in the worst case, you're the one
doing the evaluation, the human checkpoint. You're the one
looking at every page, every
change to the web page, and you tell it yes,
no? or you give it a score to let it
know if it's going well or not.
This approach works very well
for these two because they're
developers,
they write code, and so without them
having to babysit what
people are doing, they clearly define a
loop like "Let me refactory
this entire service so that it's more
efficient, that it takes up less memory,
so that tokens are reduced
by 70%, blah blah blah blah," and they give it
a well-defined task and let it
run until it reaches
that goal. So it works very well.
Good for them because this task is verifiable
. That's why they say so. I
don't write prompts anymore, I just make loops.
But in other cases this approach needs to be
looked at in detail because there
are things where, for example, it's not
automatically verifiable, it's not
deterministic and therefore we have to act
as judges or the large language model acts as
judge or we have to
have more control over what's
happening. Let's do a real
loop engineering test. So, I had
a script created that does the product between
matrices
and and evaluates how long it takes to
do this calculation, right? This is the
basic starting script and now
we use loop engineering to
optimize this frame product which
is an open problem that everyone is
trying to optimize.
So let's launch the first experiment,
matrix multiply and these are the times.
These are the dimensions of the matrices
500*500, 1000*1000, 2000*2000, 3000*
3000 and these are the times 004 018, 0019
and 0398 seconds. So now
we use GOL to optimize
algorithms, which is the best use case
because you can actually see
the experiments, the steps it takes. So
let's slashg
improve the time it takes to perform
the matrix product
with this Python script
for every test you do and
write it in a markup file and
also briefly write the changes
made
to have traceability
. And here I put it, it does a maximum of 10
optimization attempts,
so now I give it 10 steps to
self-improve. And this is now slash
gol, so it now enters a loop
without me having to go
"No, improve this, no, improve it
again" every time, no, bring it back to the way it was
before without writing prompts. I
set it a gol, a specific loop and
now it starts.
Here it has done all 10
attempts. We have the speedup here,
so it has achieved a
320x optimization in terms of
speed using the tensor cores.
Here in the optimization log we see all the
changes I made.  done, so the
original script, flot 64 by default, then
double the memory bandwidth switched to non-
pai, flot 32 blues with four threads and
cp torchu,
then patorch on the GPU started
using CUDA, up to Porch
GPU flot 16, only half precision calculation
on Tensor Core Max Truput. And here we have
the maximum, the maximum result.
This is a very simple example,
but it makes you understand the
potential of this approach,
especially in coding and apps, but you
can also use it to make it
create 3D models,
posts on social media, practically
anything, because then Cloud with the various
MCP servers you can connect it to everything and therefore
you can use loop engineering
for practically anything. I hope
you have understood, precisely, what
loop engineering is and that you
also enjoyed the whole historical excursus
made of the choices and all the loops that
have been added, precisely, in these
systems. Write me a comment below
telling me your opinion, what you think and
follow me to stay updated on the
world of AR.